FULL STACK WEB DEVELOPER

Damian Deleon

Phone: (512) 569-7525 | Email: damianmdeleon@gmail.com | Austin, TX 78727

LinkedIn: https://bit.ly/3dAlJuX | Portfolio: https://bit.ly/3dAlJuX | Portfolio: https://bit.ly/363TWPu | GitHub: https://bit.ly/364TWPu | Portfolio: https://bit.ly/364TWPu | Portfo

PROFILE

Full Stack Web Developer with a Bachelors in Business and over 20 years of experience working for companies like IBM, Facebook, Apple, and General Motors. Recognized and endorsed by former colleagues in Vendor Management and Business Performance Management. Earned a certificate from the Coding Boot Camp at the University of Texas in Austin. Skilled in the fundamentals of HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, and React.js and excited to learn more and expand my knowledge base. Efficient worker and a strategic thinker with the ability to pivot upon changing conditions. Goal is to build websites and apps that provide a practical service to people and businesses. Excited to join a team that is fast-paced and quality-driven and help them make a positive impact on the world.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: JavaScript, CSS, HTML, SQL, NoSQL

Applications: GitHub, MongoDB, MongoDB Atlas, Heroku

Tools: Express, React, Node, API, Handlebars, Bootstrap, Bootstrap React

PROJECTS

VACATION PLANNER - GROUP PROJECT

Deploy Link: https://bit.ly/3w8Z13K | **Repository**: https://bit.ly/3dz8Jpq

Summary: This app will suggest a vacation destination with the weather forecast and suggested places to

eat, based on the user

Technologies: HTML, CSS, JS, Bulma, and two API's (Open Weather API and Zomato API) **Role:** Folder structure design, Implementation of Zomato API, local storage implementation

WEATHER DASHBOARD

Deploy Link: https://bit.ly/3qFGGtJ | **Repository:** https://bit.ly/2Tuw8l3

Summary: This app is used to pull the local forecast plus a five day forecast by city for a user

Technologies: HTML, CSS, JS, Open Weather API

Role: Sole Author

WORKDAY SCHEDULER

Deploy Link: https://bit.ly/2UeZO5N **Summary:** This tool is used to keep a daily track of events scheduled for a user

Technologies: HTML, CSS, JS, Bootstrap, Font Awesome, Local Storage

Role: Sole Author

WORK EXPERIENCE

SENIOR OPERATIONS MANAGER 2013-2020

CONCENTRIX CORP (FORMERLY IBM BUSINESS PROCESS SERVICES)

AUSTIN,

TEXAS

Summary: Vendor Partner supporting several client partnerships such as **General Motors** (2013 - 2016), **Facebook** (2016 - 2018), and **Apple Inc.** (2018 - 2020). Developed and deployed performance plans based on reporting data. Oversaw the Operations of the organization in report analysis, Key Performance Indicator (KPI) management, HR policies, performance management, and motivation.

- Recognized by **Apple** for successfully onboarding 350 additional employees within a month to assist with work-from-home support as Apple stores began to close during the 2020 Pandemic
- Achieved 1% attrition rate through consistent management support and presence for the **General Motors** organization
- Won additional business In 2013 by **Facebook** to include risk analytics of their Ads Fraud Management Department by exceeding a 90% efficiency goal and the 97% quality targets consistently.

BUSINESS PROCESS MANAGER 2006-2013

IBM AUSTIN, TEXAS

Summary: Vendor Partner for **General Motors** client overseeing program and client relationship. Organized and deployed weekly strategic planning to meet KPI's and expand the business. Presented solutions to General Motors client to address emerging challenges. Provided weekly performance presentations to clients and management on behalf of the organization. Provided frequent and transparent communication with clients to ensure a positive working relationship.

- Awarded 8 "Thank You" Awards for exceptional partnering with the General Motors employees during the General Motors bankruptcy and subsequent government assistance years.
- Celebrated 90% Legal and BBB arbitration win rate compared to the 85% goal over the years between 2011 and 2013
- Developed a successful and long-standing partnership with General Motors Local Council by setting up and hosting legal seminars for employees to stay up to date on successful legal strategies and processes development

EDUCATION

UT Austin – Full Stack Web Development Bootcamp – June 2021 University of Phoenix -Austin Campus – BS Business Admin - Sept 2011